# **MANISH GUPTA**

+91 8800738793

kumarmanish1995130@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/manish-gupta-885444128 github.com/Manish-Gupta-IT/git-demo.git



## **PROFILE SUMMARY**

- A passionate software engineer enthusiastic in Software Development and having around 3 years of
  professional experience. My goal is to secure a distinct position in the progressive and prestigious
  organisation, where my skills are utilized in a best way with a scope of learning, innovation and allround career development.
- I want to implement my knowledge & Hands on experience in RESTFul web services and making APIs using Java.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor Of Technology - Major: Information Technology
Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Class (10+2) - Major: Science
Hetauda School Of Management and Social Science

Class 10

Kala Kunj Secondary English Boarding School

July 2014 – June 2018

Delhi, India

April 2012 – March 2013

Hetauda, Nepal

April 2010 – March 2011

Gaur, Nepal

## **SKILLS**

Languages: English, Hindi, Nepali

Programming: J2EE, Spring MVC, Javascript, JSP, Servlets, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Document Creation : Microsoft Office, Notepad

Tools: Eclipse, Spring Tool Suite, Postman, SQL DBX, MySQL, PostgreSQL, JBoss, Apache Tomcat

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Software EngineerJuly 2019 – PresentNewgen Software Technologies Ltd.Noida, India

• Currently, working on one of the key projects of MORTH client at Newgen Software Technologies Ltd., Noida sinceJuly 2019.

#### **Software Engineer Trainee**

Kenmax Business Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

July 2018 – July 2019 Noida, India

• Worked on Induction Feedback at Kenmax Business Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Noida.

## **PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN**

## Newgen Software Technologies Ltd.

#### **MORTH - Audit Para**

Every Govt. Organization has a specific process to perform their audits (both internal and external). Every year
auditors can perform audits and both auditors and auditee can view previous audits for reference through web
portal which will be integrated with the Newgen DMS solution. If required, auditors/auditees can attach various
documents (Digitized or E-Files) as supporting in the solution and push it to the respective officer to take proper
initiative against it.

#### Role:

- Designed the application form for Audit Para where audit schedule details such as type of audit, Audit Date From, Audit Date To etc. would be filled by the auditor using Javascript.
- Handled the action flows which have to taken at various worksteps using SQL.
- Currently, developing the process/workflow using Core Java as to how the application form would be processed from the Auditor workstep to the Auditee workstep.

# First Citizen Bank - RLOS/CLOS

• First Citizen Bank project is designed to account the flow of process of applying the loan regarding RLOS and CLOS mentioning the retail and corporate loan according to the customer requirement. So the flow of loan applying is first passes through load Tracking, Branch, Head Office & Approval, Offer Letter, Security & Legal. There are different forms were created and particular forms attached with respective workitem. This helps to overcome the problem created during the paper work for applying the loan and makes the work easy digitally.

#### Role:

- Developed several APIs which are used in this project.
- Handled the customer data migration through Utilities.
- Server Side coding using Java and implementation of RESTful Web Services.
- Also worked on the database side using MySQL server.

## **Kenmax Business Solutions Pvt. Ltd.**

## **Induction Feedback**

- This project describes that when an organization hires new employees, it must provide training to them. To know about the trainer's performance, organization takes the feedback of the trainer through this product.

Manish Kr Gupta

## Role:

- Worked on designing the Induction Feedback Form through HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, JQuery and AJAX.
- Also worked on data saving part in the backend through Core Java and SQL.

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Father's Name : Mr. Surendra Pd. Gupta

Date of Birth : 30-Jan-1995 Marital status : Single

Temporary Address : C-172, Ganesh Nagar, New Delhi Permanent Address : Ishnath-2, Province-2, Nepal

# **UNDERTAKING**

I hereby declare that all the details furnished above are true to the best of my knowledge.

Date: 04-07-2021 Place: New Delhi